# **AKSHAY G**

# Front-End Developer | JavaScript | React | Html | Css

+91 87 54 070533 akshayg2422@gmail.com Gummidipoondi, Chennai

#### **SUMMARY**

Persevering learner and diligent team player with 2.6 years of experience specializing in UI development using the React library. Skilled software engineer with expertise in AI-powered recruiting applications, HRMS, Budgie-CEM, Ticket management, Educational timeline systems, and ERP applications. You can view my portfolio here.

#### **SKILLS**

Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap, Mui, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Redux

Saga, Redux thunk, React Router, Git, GitHub, Bit bucket, Azure, Git lab, Rest, Axios, Fetch,

Scss, Firebase, i18n-js, Jitsi, validate.js, React-player, React-photo-view, React-DND,

React-Select

## **PROJECTS**

# **INTRVU SPACE** — Hiring Application (AI)

### https://www.intrvu.space/

• intrvu SPACE helps you conduct automated Interviews, Generate Reports, and Approve Candidates end to end with zero manual effort.

**Contribution:** Landing page, Login, OTP, Corporate flow, CRUD candidate flow, Settings, Job seeker flow, Report

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js

# Zeny Q — HRMS

#### https://www.zenyq.com/

• Employee management application with features like attendance and payroll management.

**Contribution:** Api integration and data normalization, Salary slip.

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, push notification

#### Quanta TMS — Ticket Management Solution

## https://www.quantatms.in/

• Enhances task and ticket management for improved collaboration.

**Contribution:** Login, OTP, Individual & Group chats, Task, Ticket, Association, Feeds, Event **Tech Stack:** React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification **Quanta EDAT** — **EduTech Application** 

#### https://www.quantaedat.com/

• Offers comprehensive programming courses with practical tasks and mock interviews.

Contribution: Course CRUD, Tasks, Topics, Schedule Interview, Online Sessions
Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js

## NS Instruments - FG — Finished Goods Management

• Optimises inventory control with streamlined stock and product management.

**Contribution:** Login, OTP, Dispatch request, Stock request and Paginated Listing **Tech Stack:** React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **React JS Developer -** 17/06/2024 - 31/10/2024

SightSpectrumTechnology Solutions (P) Ltd. - Tidel, Tiruvanmyur.

- Responsible for frontend design, development and deployment.
- Proficient in developing UI for web applications primarily on React JS
- Skilled in developing modular components to ensure scalability and maintainability
- Collaborate effectively with UI/UX designers to implement designs that enhance user experience
- Proactively troubleshoot and debug issues to ensure smooth functioning of applications
- Stay updated with the latest technologies through continuous research and self-learning
- Oversee testing protocols to maintain the quality and reliability of applications

# **React JS Developer** - 06/2022 - 15/06/2024

Leora Infotech Private Limited - Gummidipoondi, Chennai.

- Responsible for frontend design and development
- Proficient in developing UI for web applications primarily on React JS
- Skilled in developing modular components to ensure scalability and maintainability
- Collaborate effectively with UI/UX designers to implement designs that enhance user experience
- Proactively troubleshoot and debug issues to ensure smooth functioning of applications
- Stay updated with the latest technologies through continuous research and self-learning

• Oversee testing protocols to maintain the quality and reliability of applications

**Tele Marketing Assistant** - 17/03/2022 - 31/05/2022

Malayala Manorama Company Limited - Egmore, Chennai.

Payment Assistance - 30/09/2021 - 14/03/2022

MATRIMONY.COM LIMITED - Guindy, Chennai.

- As a Payment Assistant, I facilitated payments and supported users navigating the payment page.
- Utilizing chat and system calls, I addressed user concerns, convinced them of package benefits, and ensured a smooth transaction experience.

**Data Provisioning Executive - 01/2019 - 11/2019** 

Tenth Planet Technologies - Mount Road, Chennai.

• Provide customized enterprise IT solutions, centered around open source software, troubleshoot issues, and ensure compliance.

**Process Associate** - 04/2017 - 11/2017

String Information Services - Saidapet, Chennai.

 Mortgage Process Outsourcing (MPO) - tailored solutions, optimize and streamline mortgage processes, enhance efficiency, reduce costs.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bsc Computer Science - 2013 - 2016** 

Shree Chandraprabhu Jain College Minjur, Chennai.

**XII** (**HSS**) - 2011 -2013

St.Marys Matric Hr Sec Chinthala Kuppam, Gummidipoondi.

X (SSLC) - 2010 - 2011

Shanthiniketan Matric Hr Sec New Gummidipoondi.

#### LANGUAGES

Tamil: Mother Tongue English: Professional (Conversationally fluent)

Malayalam: Conversationally fluent Hindi: Writing and Reading